# **Dr. Po-Hsun Tseng**

6+ years experience of large-scale software development with C programming on the Linux system throughout my Ph.D. journey.

Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with low-level system programming (eg. device driver, Linux kernel, CPU architecture) to apply my skills at a fabless company.



## CONTACT

zengbs@gmail.com

+886 966 587 832

Hsinchu, Taiwan

https://github.com/zengbs

## **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

**Bash scripting** System programming **CUDA** 

**Pvthon** 

**Operating System** 

Linux - user Linux - kernel 

Architecture

**ARM** architecture

Software & Tools

Git Vim Gdb Valgrind

Languages

Chinese (native) **English - writing** 

**English - speaking** 

**English - listening** 

**English - reading** 

## **EDUCATION**

**6** 08/2016 - 06/2022

Ph.D. in Computational Physics National Taiwan University, Taiwan

- ullet Developed and implemented a new algorithm to reduce numerical error by  $10^6$  compared to conventional one. See Fig. 16 in (https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130).
- Designed a new approach to further promote the robustness of GAMER. The new approach was adopted in the research project led by Dr. Kuo-Chuan Pan from Tsing Hua University. See the merged branch: (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/pull/60)
- Worked on improving the GAMER collaborated with Dr. Tzihong Chiueh and Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive. See the Section References.
- A main contributor of the GAMER. See: (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/graphs/contributors)
- Built NIS, NFS, and Linux cluster from scratch with colleagues and worked with Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive to bootstrap simulations for research.

## **WORK HISTORY**

**12/2014 - 01/2016** 

Circuit designer **♥** TDK corporation, Singapore Design the circiut of surface acoustic wave(SAW) filters

**6** 08/2013 - 08/2014

Military Service

# **EDUCATION**

**1** 09/2011 - 07/2013

♥ National Taiwan University, Taiwan

M.Sc. in Physics

**1** 09/2006 - 07/2011

**♀** National Central University, Taiwan

**B.Sc.** in Mathematics

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Nonverbal communication Open mindedness Active listening **Patience** Mutual respect Teamwork **Brainstorming** Collaboration

## **GENERAL SKILLS**

Numerical algorithm Large-scale project cscope makefile

**GNU** autotools

## **PUBLICATIONS**

An adaptive mesh, GPU-accelerated, and error minimized special relativistic hydrodynamics code

Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh

Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315
https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130

The symmetry problem of the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles: A proof-of-concept study
Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang, Hsi-Yu Schive, Chun-Yen Chen, Tzihong Chiueh

2022 preprint

## **TALKS**

• An adaptive-mesh, GPU-accelerated, and optimally error-controlled special relativistic hydrodynamics code Oral (remote), American Center for Physics College Park, U.S.A

Mar. 2021

A new and accurate code for simulating special relativistic hydrodynamics
 Oral, Annual Meeting of the Physical Society of Taiwan, NPTU.

Feb. 2020

#### REFERENCES

- Please send an appointment letter to request a call. 😃
- Dr. Tzihong Chiueh

Distinguished Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- chiuehth@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- +886 2 3366 8628
- Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- hyschive@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **\** +886 2 3366 8644
- Dr. Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astronomy, National Tsing Hua University

- Hsinchu 30013, Taiwan
- hyang@phys.nthu.edu.tw
- **4886** 3 574 2953